The following is a conversation with Jan LeCun, his second time on the podcast.
He is the chief AI scientist at Meta, formerly Facebook, professor at NYU, touring award
winner, one of the seminal figures in the history of machine learning and artificial
intelligence, and someone who is brilliant and opinionated in the best kind of way, and
so is always fun to talk to.
So, this is a Lex Friedman podcast.
To support it, please check out our sponsors in the description.
And now, here's my conversation with Jan LeCun.
You co-wrote the article, Self-Supervised Learning, The Dark Matter of Intelligence.
Great title, by the way, with Ishan Mizra.
So let me ask, what is self-supervised learning, and why is it the dark matter of intelligence?
I'll start by the dark matter part.
There is obviously a kind of learning that humans and animals are doing that we currently
are not reproducing properly with machines, with AI, right?
So the most popular approaches to machine learning today are, or paradigms, I should
say, are supervised learning and reinforcement learning.
And they are extremely inefficient.
Supervised learning requires many samples for learning anything, and reinforcement learning
requires a ridiculously large amount of time.
There's a large number of trial and errors for a system to learn anything.
And that's why we don't have self-driving cars.
That's a big leap from one to the other.
Okay, so to solve difficult problems, you have to have a lot of human annotation for
supervised learning to work.
And to solve those difficult problems with reinforcement learning, you have to have some
way to maybe simulate that problem such that you can do that large-scale.
Kind of learning that reinforcement learning requires.
Right.
So how is it that, you know, most teenagers can learn to drive a car in about 20